CLAYTON WHITTAKER

+1 (925) 259-1450

clayton-whittaker

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

clayton.whittaker@gmail.com

San Francisco, California

clay099

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer who believes that technology can improve the user experience to ensure client satisfaction and deliver sustained business growth. For the past 5 years I worked in financial services and was charged with automating processes to make them more efficient. This experience led to a real passion for technology and automation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, , Python, SQL

Front-end: ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Axios, React Testing Library, Jasmine, Sass

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, Flask, PostgreSQL, Jest, Express, MongoDB, Passport

Development and Deployment: GitHub, Heroku, Netlify

PROJECTS

Stock Tracking Application | June 2020

- Created a stock tracking application designed to let users create a portfolio and track its performance over time without needing to spend money purchasing the stocks.
- Tech Stack: Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, WTForms, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, PostgreSQL

Peer-to-Peer Outsourcing Application | June 2020

- Created a peer-to-peer outsourcing application (front-end & back-end) designed to let users post handyman projects need assistance with. Tradesmen can sign in and bid on project. Users then select a tradesman to proceed with and complete real-world projects.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Material-UI, Jest & React Testing Library, Express, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

Springboard | San Francisco

April 2020 - Present

- Software Engineer with a full stack focus including front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms.
- 700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects.

Enrizen Financial Group | Sydney, Australia

Jan 2014 - Sep 2019 Jan 2017 - Sep 2019

Manager | Product Development & Automation

- Spearheaded Insurance Broking transition to a new software platform to increase automation by 25%
- Launched a white label stock broking offering, including software selection and transition for an execution framework and a separate compliance platform. Allowing traders, the ability to execute stock trades while keeping a Chinese wall for ongoing deals.
- Introduced and administered Private Funding and Insurance Underwriting entities, generating profitability within 9 months.
- Consolidated from multiple industry specific CRM systems to Salesforce as the one company wide CRM allowing one client record for consumers who may utilize multiple services and allow marketing to create targeted campaigns.
- Continued Client Relationship Management responsibilities

Senior Associate | Client Relationship Manager

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

- Attained an 15% average yearly increase in Gross Written Premium (GWP) and 17.5% in Brokerage income (Commission + Broker Fee) on a mature portfolio.
- Financial analysis assisting public companies with acquisitions and transactions between \$5m to \$50m including lead analyst role on a \$35m acquisition. This role included financial analysis, forecasting, and risk assessment including preparation of the investor deck and prospectus

Associate | Client Manager

Mar 2014 - Dec 2015

- Development and execution of General Insurance Program sales pipeline. Increased GWP by 20%
- Assistance to Executive Director of Finance from initial sales meeting to applications submission and bank credit negotiations.

Sales Intern

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

- Business development of General Insurance Sales Pipeline for Senior Executives, including cold calls, warm calls and lead generation.
- Assistance to Senior Executives with preparing insurance quote slips for General Insurers review, increasing team profitability by 20%

EDUCATION

CPA Foundations Couse (Equivalent to Bachelor of Accounting) | CPA Australia Certificate IV – General Insurance Broking | Kaplan Professional Diploma - Finance and Mortgage Broking Management | Kaplan Professional Bachelor of Business Administration | Macquarie University

2015 - 20182014

2014

2010 - 2013